welcome back
today we are going to move on to the UEV tier
after making the intro quest
we have to decide on which branch we want to make our first progress
and getting the last Circuit assembler out of the way didn't unlock any further path
that's because to make use of it
we also need the motors of the new tier
but those require a material that isn't found in our galaxy
to adventure that far
we are going to need a mother ship
however
to build one
we have to first make a shuttle
which is crafted with something called radox polymer
which is an endgame plastic
which requires us to build the last chemical chain of this series
however
the starting point is something called xenoxene
which is produced by the most delicate bacteria there is
xenoxene xenoxsis
however
this is not even a bacteria we can find in nature
we have to do a lot of weird DNA messing around in our biolab to obtain that species
it all starts from taking some excrement bacteria out of a rotten spider eye
once we isolated it
we take it into a vat
where we will be making lots of biohazardous fluid
by working that stuff
we can extract all sorts of useful ingredients that we are going to need soon
then
we start working on the basic bacteria for xenoxene
Barnardfis arboriatoris
which can be picked out of some barnarda logs
the next step is to try to extract its DNA
and this is a low success chance
only 1 out of 20 samples succeeded
now we want to analyze this sample
and save it on a data orb
however the process is delicate
and it often fails at saving the correct data
so after stocking up a lot of stuff to do more tries
we managed to get a bunch of DNA samples to try again
this time luckily
we got the data analyzed correctly at the first try
now we use that and the data from another bacteria
to create the plasmid for the new bacteria we want to create
once we get it
we use it to mutate the TCetiEis bacteria into xenoxene xenoxsis
which we shall take to a new set of vats
where we will finally be preparing xenoxene
the basis for radox production
once we have that
it's just a matter of a processing chain of less than a dozen machines
to get the radox polymer
with that
we can now craft the lightweight plates required for the shuttle
meanwhile we also make its schematics
and the parts for our upcoming mother ship
once everything is ready
we build our new spaceship
however for now
more than a spaceship it is a satellite
since it has no engines
so we quickly order a thruster for our ship
once the new engine is in place
and filled with naquadah fuel
we can move our ship
but it appears that this engine is not strong enough to move us to a new galaxy
we could increase its size or add a second one
but we are instead going to upgrade to an ion thruster
which can reach 10 times higher speeds
with the new engine equipped
we can now move our mother ship to the Ra solar system
and thanks to the ion thrusters
this will only take 13 minutes
once we reach destination
we quickly move to the main belt
which was the actual destination that made us build the whole mother ship
this is not a planet
but a belt of asteroids orbiting the RA star
our mother ship is too big
and can't risk getting damaged by the asteroids
so we get closer by using the shuttle
and then we start wandering around
until we find what we came here for
tengam
once we found an asteroid made out of the ore
we have to face some guards
and then the mining operation can start
we are going to hide from the swarms of robots inside the asteroid
where we will be setting up a void miner
and this miner is going to mine the void literally
once we get back
after extracting the raw tengam from its ore
we proceed into refining it with an electromagnetic separator
and the first usage we have for the new material is an electromagnet
to speed up its refinement process
and then we can finally craft the new motors
the first UEV thing we want to make is a space pump
however that highlighted a bottleneck
we are too slow at compressing infinity
luckily
there is now an upgrade to the neutronium compressor
however to craft it
we need super dense plates which must be made with a hot isostatic pressurization unit
which is a machine which has to be toggled on and off to avoid overheating
so here we have it built
with a sensor that will stop it when it heats too much
so we better use this only when required
to avoid extra clogging
and thus we have our new neutronium compressor
which is going to be way faster at compressing Infinity Catalyst
and thus we can have our new space pumping station
the first gas we will want to pump is hydrogen
however that tank could be small
so we go back to our compressor
to craft something that can carry more fluid
a digital singularity cell
that thing will allow us to store all the hydrogen we could possibly need
we already passed the tank by 100 times
but the cell is still almost empty
moving on to get the new circuits
after photonically enriching an americium doped wafer
we find out we need some more purified water to cut it
so we go back to our water line
and add more steps after the extreme temperature fluctuation plant
namely the high energy laser purification unit
which will pass the water under lasers of all the colors
to make sure it hits any possible thing that could have survived the 1000 Kelvin temperature
and then the residual decontaminant degasser purification unit
which has some complex logic
and will require us to decode its signals
and act accordingly
and since we are not experienced enough with Redstone
we just brute force it with Steve's factory manager
and with this purified water
we can now cut our optically perfected wafers
next
we add some nanites to our wafers with the help of a strong laser and some plasma
and we smash everything with some extra purified water in our sledge hammer
to expose some circuit material
we bring that materials to our space elevator
where with the help of some space assemblers
we upload the raw materials above the clouds
for some operations that require a zero gravity ambient
then we download the so assembled RAM
next
we start preparing a new factory area
for the stuff we will build with all that space RAM
then we make one floor for the basic optical processor
one for the optical assembly
one for the computer
and finally one for the main frame
now that we have this new circuit
we shall put it to good use
and the first machine we can build with our new circuits is
the dimensionally transcendent plasma forge
that machine is going to require a lot of materials
not to mention the amount of blocks for the structure
we will probably want to make it out of the new Infinity coils
which other than Infinity
will now also require circuits
and it is now time to put our AE2 system to test again
crafting just the controller is going to take some time
so in the meanwhile
we can prepare the other stuff that is going to be needed
the plasma Forge uses a fuel dimensionally transcendent catalysts
which are made by mixing together many different plasmas
since we do not have a plasma mixer
we shall make those as a multi step process with our normal industrial mixers
and that is going to be a really slow and power intensive process
even with our 12 socketed machines
and after mixing the raw plasmas
we give a finishing touch with our new laser
going back to our DTPF crafting
after taking note of one of the weirdest bottlenecks
we notice that our 6 general purpose assembly line aren't enough
so we added some more
and we needed a second data bank
to share all of the data sticks from the old one
and all of those rainbow spaghetti reminded us that
we must also add one more colored laser to our battery
to bring power to the location where we are going to build the new machine
which in the meantime
we have completed in all of it majesty
this block is going to greatly reduce the amount of resources we need to process some of the endgame materials
or drastically cut the crafting time of working others
but what we want right now
is completely new and weird stuff
such as tesseracts
however before getting into crafting those
there is some stuff we have to worry about
the main cost of running this structure is in the catalysts used as fuel
we can cut the cost by half by never letting this machine shut down
so once we start it
we will have a system to keep it running on slower stuff perpetually
to do so
we simply start throwing in stuff to work whenever the crafting input bus for on demand craftings empties
and as you can see
we are slowly building up a discount in fuel usage
but we can do better
the thing we are passively doing while no crafts are queued is hypogen
hypogen is a really useful material
which for example
can cut the recurrence of crafting batteries
or help us make better fuels for our generators
but the main issue is that to make hypogen we are using hypogen
there is a better recipe with higher yield
and no hypogen usage
but that requires hypogen coils
the issue is that we are making 19 litres per second when our DTPF would otherwise be idling
to make new coils we need two millions of it
that's around 40 hours
the other way we have for making hypogen is with fusion
but that requires dragon blood
we had obtained some of that stuff when we slew the Ender Dragon
but that won't be enough
since we are also going to need a lot of that stuff in a couple of tiers
we shall look for a better source
but that's a story for the next episode
but before greeting
we shall find a morale for this episode
and I think here the lesson is that
the real lesson was within us all of the time
bye bye
欢迎回来！
今天我们要进入UEV电压
完成序章后
我们必须决定先发展哪个分支
做出最后一个电路装配机并没有解锁其他任务
那是因为想利用它
我们还需要UEV马达
但这需要一种我们星系没有的物质
想去那么远的地方
母舰必不可少
然而
想做一个
我们得先做个穿梭机
它需要拉多X聚合物
这是后期的一种塑料
需要我们建造这个系列的最后一个化学链
然而
它的起点是一种叫做异氙的东西
它是由最脆弱的细菌产生的
异氙菌
然而
自然界甚至找不到这种细菌
为了得到它
我们不得不在实验室混合各种DNA
先是从腐烂蜘蛛眼中提取粪便细菌
一旦分离出大肠杆菌
我们把它放进培养缸里
我们将制造大量生物危害液体
通过处理那些东西
我们可以获得各种马上要用到的原料
然后
我们开始研究异氙的前置细菌
巴纳德菌
它们可以从巴纳德树木中挑选出来
下一步是尝试提取它的DNA
成功机率很低
20个样本中只会成功1个
现在我们分析这个样本
并将其保存在数据球上
然而，这个过程不确定性很高
它经常无法保存正确的数据
所以在储备了很多东西来做更多的尝试之后
我们得到了一堆DNA样本来重试
这次，幸运的是
我们一发入魂
现在我们用它和另一种细菌的数据
来创造异氙菌所需的质粒
一旦我们得到它
我们用它把鲸鱼座T星E菌变异为异氙菌
然后将它带到一套新的培养缸里
我们将在那里制备异氙
用作拉多X产线的基础
一旦我们有了那个
只需要堆不到十二个机器
便能轻松获得拉多X聚合物
有了那个
我们现在可以制作母舰所需的轻质合金板
同时我们还制作了它的设计图
还有即将到来的母舰的零件
一旦一切准备就绪
直接建造母舰
然而目前
它更像一个卫星
因为它没有引擎
所以很快为我们的船订购了一个推进器
一旦新引擎就位
并装满硅岩燃料
飞船便可以动起来了
但是这个引擎似乎还不足以把我们带到一个新的星系
我们可以增加它的尺寸或添加第二个
但我们要升级到离子推进器
这可以达到10倍以上的速度
配备完新的引擎
我们现在可以把母舰移到Ra星系了
多亏了离子推进器
这只需要13分钟
一旦我们到达目的地
我们快速移动到主轨道
这就是我们建造整艘母舰的真正目的地
这不是行星
而是围绕RA星的小行星带
我们的母舰太大了
不能冒被小行星击中的险
所以我们用穿梭机靠近
我们在四处逛逛
直到找到目标
生磁
一旦我们发现了一颗由矿石构成的小行星
解决掉一些守卫
然后采矿作业就可以开始了
我们要躲避小行星内部成群的机器人
在那里设置一个虚空矿厂
就和字面上的一样
它将挖掘虚空
一旦我们回去
从矿石中提炼出生磁后
我们继续用电磁离析器精炼它
这种新材料的第一个用途是电磁铁
用来加快精炼速度
然后我们就可以制作新的电动马达
我们的第一个UEV装置是太空钻机
然而，这展露了一个瓶颈
无尽催化剂压缩得太慢了
幸运地
我们可以升级中子压缩机
然而要制作它
我们需要用热等静压装置制造的超致密板
这是一台必须反复开关以避免过热的机器
所以我们起了一台
带有一个传感器
当它过热时会停止它
所以我们最好只在需要时使用它
以避免额外的堵塞
由于我们有了新的中子压缩机
压缩无尽催化剂的速度快得多了
这样我们就有了新的太空钻机
我们要抽的第一种气体是氢气
然而，这个量子缸可能显得很小
所以回到我们的压缩机
制造能携带更多液体的东西
数字奇点单元
它可以储存我们需要的所有氢气
我们已经存超过量子缸100倍容量了
但元件还是几乎是空的
继续制作新电路
在光子富集掺杂镅的晶圆之后
我们发现需要更纯净的水才能切割
所以我们回到净化水线
并在五级水厂后添加更多步骤
即高能激光净化装置
它将用各种颜色的激光照射水
以确保它击中任何可能在1000K温度幸存下来的东西
然后是残留去污剂脱气器净化装置
它有一些复杂的逻辑
并要求我们解码它的信号
并采取相应行动
既然我们对红石不太熟练
所以使用SFM与它硬碰硬
有了这种纯净水
我们现在可以切割光学性质完美的晶圆
接下来
我们在强激光和等离子体的帮助下
向晶圆中添加纳米蜂群
在锻造锤内配合净化水砸碎一切
来暴露出一些电路材料
我们把那些材料带到太空电梯
在一些太空组装机的帮助下
我们将原材料上云
做低重力环境下的处理
然后再下载如此装配的内存
接下来
我们准备一个新的厂区
量产使用了太空内存的光学电路系列
我们为基本的光学处理器做一层
光学处理器集群一层
光学处理器超级电脑一层
最后，光学处理器主机一层
现在我们有了新电路
我们将好好利用它
我们用新电路制造的第一台机器是
超维度等离子锻炉
那台机器需要很多材料
更不用说众多的结构方块了
我们想做无尽等级的DTPF
现在无尽线圈除了无尽
还需要电路板来制造
现在是时候再次压力测试AE了
光是制作控制器就需要一些时间
所以与此同时
我们可以准备其他需要的东西
DTPF使用的超维度燃料
它们是由许多不同的等离子体混合制成的
因为我们没有等离子搅拌机
我们将使用搅拌机来分步完成
这将是一个非常缓慢和耗能的过程
12个能源仓的机器都跟不上
混合原始等离子体后
我们用新的激光刻蚀机做最后润色
回到DTPF制作
在注意到奇怪的瓶颈之后
我们发现6条通用装配线是不够的
所以我们又加了一些
我们需要第二个数据库
来共享旧数据库的所有数据
那些混乱的激光管道提醒我们
我们必须再添加一条激光管道
给我们要建造新机器的地方供电
与此同时
我们已经完成奇观的建设
这个多方块结构将大幅度减少
制造后期材料所需的原料
也可以大幅度减少一些材料的制作时间
但是我们现在想要的
是全新的奇怪东西
比如粗制超立方体
然而，在制作这些之前
有些事我们得担心
运行DTPF的主要成本在于催化剂燃料
我们可以通过不关闭这台机器来减少一半的成本
所以一旦开始
我们将保持其在低耗材的情况下一直运行
为此
只要主动制作的输入总线清空
我们便加入维持机器运行的原料
如你所见
燃料损耗正在慢慢下降
但我们可以做得更好
当没有材料排队时
将被动生产的是海珀珍
海珀珍是一种非常有用的材料
例如
可以截断电池的套娃
或者给发电机制造更好的燃料
但问题是，海珀珍的合成套娃了
有一个更高产的配方
并且不使用海珀珍
但那需要海珀珍线圈
问题是，在DTPF待机时
我们将被动生产19L/s的海珀珍
而我们需要2ML
大约40小时
另一种制造海珀珍的方法是核聚变
但那需要龙血
我们在杀死末影龙时得到了一些
但这还不够
我们在其他电压也会需要很多龙血
我们应该寻找它更好的来源
但这是下一集的故事
但在Welcome back之前
我们要鼓起士气
我认为今天的教训是
真正的教训一直在我们心中
拜拜
（之后用英文缩写DTPF指代）